Guide to the Arthur Jeffery Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Contents List
  - Notes on the Mufaddaliyat, undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Tradition, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Umar II and Leo III, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Arabian Culture, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Arabian History, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Arabic Literature--Notes on Arabian Nights, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography of Gnosticism, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Complete Reader on Islam, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 5-6)
  - Gnosticism, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Materials on the ????? Questions, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Gnosticism, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Ancient History, 1914 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Bible--Canon and Text, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Archaeology of the Old Testament, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Bible--Book of Daniel, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
  - Exercise Book--Canon and Text, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Greek Versions of the Old Testament, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Interpreter's Dictionary of the Bible, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Old Testament Lecture Notes, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - African Language Families, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - American Indian Languages, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Austronesian Languages, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Language Families of the World as Illustrated from the Lord's Prayer, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Semito-Hamitic Family, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Divinity Notes--Theoretical Mechanics, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the History of Religion, undated (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Philosophy Notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Psychology--Method of Teaching--College Lectures, 1914 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Religion, Divinity, Theology, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Seminary Lectures on Comparative Religion, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Chaucer--The Nun's Priests' Tale, 1918-1919 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Notebook
    - Greek Philosophy, 1916 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Greek Philosophy, Semitic Studies, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - History of Philosophy III, 1916 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Logic, undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Seminar Courses on Higher Criticism of Quran, 1923 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Published Material--Les Origines des Legendes Musulmanes, 1933 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Development of the Alphabet, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Germanic Philology Notebooks I and II, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Language and Philology Notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Notes on Science of Language, 1932 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - School Notebooks with Language Lessons (seven volumes), undated, 1916 (Box 51, Folder 5-11)
  - Photostats of Manuscript--Azhar, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Photostats of Manuscript--Berlin, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Photostats of Manuscript--Berlin No. 578, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Greek Language Exercises, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Languages--Greek, Albanian, Armenian, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Language Specimens, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Notebook on Language, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Notebook on Language and Prayer, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Tables of Alphabets, undated (Box 53)
  - Quran Subject Index Files, T-Z, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Vocabulary Notecards, A-Z, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Books, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Book Notes, undated
    - Chapters 1-2 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 5-7 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 8-10 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 11-14 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Subject Notes, undated
    - A-H (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - I-Z (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Notes on the Book of the Himyarites, undated (Box 56)
    - A-G (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - H-Q (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - R-Z (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Works Containing Information on Christian Arabs, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Microfilm from Cairo, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Subject Notecards, undated
    - A-C (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - D (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - E-F (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - G (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - H (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - A, (4 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 6-9)
    - B (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Subject Notecards, N-Z, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Canon of the Old Testament, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
  - Photostats (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Notebook
    - Advanced Ethics, 1917 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Advanced Logic, 1916 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Classical History, 1913 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Geology, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Metaphysics Lectures, 1917 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Published Material
    - Abrik der Kirchengelchichte, 1906 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Agyptische Grammatik, 1894 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Christian Essentials: A Re-statement for the People, 1907 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - The Rise of Christianity, 1907 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Semitic Religions, undated
    - A-L (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - M-Z (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Subject Notes, A-Z, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Subject Notes II, A-Z, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Subject Index Files, undated
    - H-I (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - I-L (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of Arabic mss. (2 v.); Corpus Lectionum Variorum in Qoranum by A. Jerrery (3 volumes). (Box Flat Box 661)
  - Al-Muhtasas, L'ibn Jinni, Egy. Lib. Qira'at. 78 (Box Flat Box 661)
  - Fragments of the Sahîh of Al-Bukhârî (Box Flat Box 662)